

Ozan Biber

Date of birth: 09/03/1994 | **Nationality:** Turkish | **Gender** Male | (+90) 5064015694 |

oznbiber@gmail.com | Skype: ozan.biber |

Dedebaşı Mahallesi 6113 Sokak No:6 Kat:5 Daire:11, Karşıyaka, 35560, İzmir, Turkey

About me: I am a versatile software engineer with two years of experience in web applications and mobile applications. Experienced with; - Full-stack web app/service/API development (Spring, Hibernate, Codelgniter, Phalcon, REST/JSON, SOAP/XML etc.) - Unit and integration testing - Object-Oriented Design and Programming, well-known patterns, architectures - Scrum/Agile methodologies - Working in multi-cultural teams with people from different disciplines

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/08/2019 – CURRENT – İzmir, Turkey **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER –** YAŞAR BILGI

- Working as a full-stack developer on company's multiple different in-house projects based on Java/Spring Framework.
- Analyzing and developing new features, fixing bugs, enhancing code quality, general efficiency and performance of application code.
- Architecting integration of new side-products into the core product.
- Working closely with DevOps, QA, analysis and 3rd party integrator teams to meet the requirements, keep products stable, foresee and eliminate roadblocks or potential obstacles.
- Took ownership as well as did hands-on coding on key features i.e. migration of an old SAP-based existing web service with 50+ APIs into a more effective, performant, developer-friendly, robust REST API for the mobile client. Also technically lead the peer developers and testers working on this.
- Getting involved in product releases, monitoring and hot fixing of the live issues.
- Performing code-review of 10+ peer developers.
- Mentoring junior, interns and other peer developers on various technical and non-technical topics.
- Taking initiative for introducing new tech into team as well as promoting well-known software development principles, industry standards and making best use of what current used language and frameworks offer
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Framework, JPA/Hibernate, Hazelcast, H2/PostgreSQL, JUnit/Mockito, Liquibase, Thymeleaf, ActiveMQ, Git/GitLab, Jenkins, Graylog, Tomcat.

27/08/2018 - 21/09/2018 - İzmir, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP - YAŞAR BILGI

- Developed a web application called "Dijital.Rehber" which is used in internal of firm to help employees for finds internal phone numbers.
- Tech Stack: |ava, Spring Boot, Spring Security, PostgreSQL, Thymeleaf, HTML/CSS/|avaScript/Bootstrap/|Query

Izmir, Turkey

15/06/2017 – 15/09/2017 – Sandusky/OHIO, United States **LIFE GUARD** – KALAHARI RESORTS&CONVENTIONS

- Taking measures against possible hazards in water park and to intervene in case of danger.
- $\,^\circ\,$ Raising awareness about the importance of human life.
- Training with customers who want to surf

Sandusky, OHIO, United States

11/07/2016 - 29/07/2016 - İzmir, Turkey

HARDWARE INTERN - DOKUZ EYLÜL ÜNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES

- To provide all kinds of information processing infrastructure necessary for the functioning of the institution and its existence in the future.
- To provide services in hardware, software, systems, technical service services and training works for institutions
- In areas where we are responsible, to find solutions to problems as quickly as possible.

• To create a better information systems infrastructure in the future; to provide the necessary support by presenting the automation and equipment that will provide continuous improvement and development in education, teaching, research and application in accordance with my university.

Izmir, Turkey

20/07/2015 - 18/09/2015 - İzmir, Turkey

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SOFTWARE DEVELOPER – GLM MÜHENDISLIK ELEKTRIK SISTEMLERI İTH. İHR. SAN. VE TİC. A.Ş.

- Creating and editing the required excel tables
- Developed a software which is running on Excel based Visual Basic
- Designed electric panos using AUTOCAD

Izmir, Turkey

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2012 - 09/07/2021 - İzmir, Turkey

BACHELOR DEGREE OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING - Dokuz Eylül University

01/09/2010 - 01/06/2012 - İzmir, Turkey

COMPLETE HIGH SCHOOL EDUCATION - Bornova Anadolu Lisesi

01/09/2008 - 01/06/2010 - Kütahya, Turkey

HIGH SCHOOL - Nafi Güral Fen Lisesi

01/09/2000 - 01/06/2008 - İzmir, Turkey

COMPLETE ELEMENTARY AND SECONDARY EDUCATION - Cumhuriyet İlköğretim Okulu

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): TURKISH

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	B2	B2	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

PROJECTS

Projects that I participated

- dijital.sirket
- dijital.rehber
- o dijital.form
- e-Commerce

Educational Projects on University

C#

- Sudoku
- ∘ 2048
- Minefield
- Snake

JAVA

- Tanks, Cargo Firm Management System
- Student Internship Management System
- Traffic Simulator that prevents traffic jam
- Search Engine

C

- Program which converts both XML to JSON and JSON to XML
- Program which implements KD Trees for indexing of multidimensional data
- A secure instant messaging application with using socket programming
- Car monitor that shows current sensor values of working car

Java/HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PostgreSQL

Job Search Web Site

C/C++ with Arduino IDE and Gas sensors

Sensor Network about Indoor Air Qualification

Android Studio

Captain's Guide Mobile Application

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

- While working at the various companies I have got work experience on multiple projects and various technoogies.
- While studying at the university I worked and participated in quite a few projects at the same time so I can say that I have got time management and multitasking skills, also I can easily prioritize tasks.
- Taking part in the these projects as group leader, I have acquired good skills of the way how to give the necessary instructions, exert influence and become a leader.
- Integrate into all team situations easily, possessing a personable nature that is open to teamwork and cooperation.
- I own good analytical and creative abilities.
- Finish tasks on time with a reliably high level of quality.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and interpersonal skills

- · Confident, articulate, great communication skills gained through my experience and working life.
- While studying at the university, I had a chance to work on group projects, have learned to convincingly argue
 my position to the team members, to overcome conflicts and make compromises.
- Through the internship at school and different companies, I have improved oratory skills.